sharpbrains.com 2010-06-21

# Your Privacy | SharpBrains

**SharpBrains, Inc PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF SERVICE**  
Effective Date: November 1, 2006

**INTRODUCTION  
**This Privacy Policy applies to information that users transmit to SharpBrainsÂ  through SharpBrainsÂ  website at <http://www.sharpbrains.com/> (the “Site”).  
Â 

SharpBrains is committed to your privacy. This Privacy Policy is designed to inform you of what information we collect from you on our Site and how we and our affiliates use that information.  
Â 

To put it simply: We will not sell, share or trade personal information we collect about you with any outside company for marketing or solicitation without your permission.  
Â 

Please direct any questions regarding this Privacy Policy to us by email at [customerservice@sharpbrains.com](mailto:customerservice@sharpbrains.com) or by phone at 888-SHARP-OK.  
Â 

Â 

**WHAT WE COLLECT AND WHEN  
Â ** **Personally Identifiable Information  
**We collect personally identifiable information on our Site:Â 

We collect personally identifiable information on our Site:Â 

  * When you purchase goods or services from us;
  * When you send email or comment through the Site;

The types of information collected include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, name, age, credit card information, billing and shipping addresses, email address, telephone number, and additional contact and transaction-related information, as well as any additional information you choose to include in communications to us.  
Â 

We consider each of the above types of information to be “Personally Identifiable Information” because it is individually identifiable information about you.  
Â 

Â 

**Other Information  
Â ** **In the following circumstances we collect information that is not personally identifiable:Â  ** **In the following circumstances we collect information that is not personally identifiable:Â  **

 ****In the following circumstances we collect information that is not personally identifiable:Â  

  * When you complete forms on the Site, compose web reflective journals, or correspond with us by post, phone or fax we may store portions of those communications; or
  * When you navigate the Site, we log various types of information to help manage and improve our Site, services, and marketing, in general and for you in particular. (For example, we identify items such as domains and browser types to understand how our Site is used and to report these statistics in the aggregate to the vendors that manage the technology of the Site. We also record your IP address and any information you enter and we keep track of which pages you click on.)

Â 

**Cookies, etc.**  
Â 

Like many websites, we use cookies and other standard web technology to collect information for our own use.  
Â 

A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie and to permit you to refuse it. In some cases refusing a cookie will hamper your navigation of our Site.  
Â 

Cookies make it easier for you to use the site and for us to offer opt-in and opt-out opportunities, and they enable us to follow your navigation through the site and customize it to your interests. They allow us to remember your identity and preferences so we can display content appropriate for you and your interests and so we can better market and sell our products and services to you.  
Â 

Although we contract with third parties to manage the use of these technologies, the information is only used to help manage our own websites and deliver products and information to you. The third parties are obligated by contract to keep the information confidential and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose.  
Â   
Â 

**HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION**  
Â 

We use your personally identifiable information (and at times other information we collect) to:Â 

  * Authenticate your visits;
  * Send you information and products; or
  * Help us make you aware of and provide services and products that may be of interest to you.

We also use the information to manage and improve our Site.  
Â 

If you have opted in to receiving marketing information, such as newsletters or notices about new products and services that may become available, we use your personal information to customize and deliver that information to you.  
Â 

Â 

**LIMITED DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES**  
Â 

We do not share personally identifiable information with our affiliates except in order to fulfill your orders as requested. We do not disclose your personally identifiable information to unaffiliated third parties.  
Â 

We also disclose personally identifiable information as permitted or required by law or as required by subpoena, search warrant, or other legal process.  
Â 

As our business evolves, we may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including information provided by you, in connection with a merger, reorganization or sale of some or all of our assets or in the event of bankruptcy. In any such event, personally identifiable and other information may be one of the assets transferred. We will post notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.  
Â 

**CHOICE  
Â ** ******Choosing NOT to disclose personal information  
Â ** **You are not required to register to gain access to many areas of the Site. If you use the Site’s personalized services, however, we will treat your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.  
Â ** **You are not required to register to gain access to many areas of the Site. If you use the Site’s personalized services, however, we will treat your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.Â  ** **MORE ON PRIVACY  
Â ** ******Children’s online privacy protection  
Â ** **SharpBrains understands the importance of protecting children’s privacy, especially in an online environment. The Site is not designed for or directed at children. It is our policy not to knowingly collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 13.  
Â **

You are not required to register to gain access to many areas of the Site. If you use the Site’s personalized services, however, we will treat your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.Â SharpBrains understands the importance of protecting children’s privacy, especially in an online environment. The Site is not designed for or directed at children. It is our policy not to knowingly collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 13.Â  **Links to third party sites  
Â ** **The Site contains links to third party websites. We assume no responsibility for the information practices of those websites. We encourage visitors to review each site’s privacy policy before disclosing any personal information on that site.  
Â ** **The Site contains links to third party websites. We assume no responsibility for the information practices of those websites. We encourage visitors to review each site’s privacy policy before disclosing any personal information on that site.Â  ** **Phishing  
Â ** **We do not and will not, at any time, request personal information in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is one of our priorities. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission at<http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/alerts/alt127.pdf>  
Â **

The Site contains links to third party websites. We assume no responsibility for the information practices of those websites. We encourage visitors to review each site’s privacy policy before disclosing any personal information on that site.Â We do not and will not, at any time, request personal information in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is one of our priorities. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission at Â  **Security  
Â ** **The Site uses one or more of SSL encryption, firewalls and self-updating anti-virus software to protect personal information. User purchase information is encrypted.  
Â ** **The Site uses one or more of SSL encryption, firewalls and self-updating anti-virus software to protect personal information. User purchase information is encrypted.Â  ** **CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**  
Â 

The Site uses one or more of SSL encryption, firewalls and self-updating anti-virus software to protect personal information. User purchase information is encrypted.Â Â We may make changes to this Privacy Statement at any time. However, we will attempt to notify you via email beforehand of any material change and provide you with the opportunity to opt-out. The most current version of the Privacy Policy can be found at <http://sharpbrains.com/z/your-privacy/>Â 

Â 

**CONTACT  
****Â  ** **Please direct any questions regarding this Privacy Policy to us by email at[customerservice@sharpbrains.com](mailto:customerservice@sharpbrains.com) or by phone at 888-SHARP-OK.  
Â Â ** **Please direct any questions regarding this Privacy Policy to us by email at or by phone at 888-SHARP-OK.Â  Â **

 ****Please direct any questions regarding this Privacy Policy to us by email at or by phone at 888-SHARP-OK.Â  Â
